<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-23T00:35:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Robert Behny</title><entry><title type="html">Lost at Sea Why Risk It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lost at Sea Why Risk It" /><published>2018-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2180.png" alt="image" />
I’ve recently seen some commentary that Personal Locator Beacons (PLB) aren’t needed with Ocean Rowing adventures/ expeditions/ trips.</p>

<p>I think that’s a foolish mindset and doesn’t acknowledge the many benefits that this personal device gives you.</p>

<p>Every ocean going vessel should have an Emergency Position Indicating Radio Beacon (EPIRB), a supersized PLB that relays your GPS coordinates and the device ID (which has been registered to a vessel or person with PLBs).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2181.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>What is a EPIRB? <a href="http://www.epirb.com/">Link</a></p>

<p>The idea is that if you’re in grave danger, turning on this device can alert the US Coast Guard or national rescue organization that a situation is unfolding. This device is mobile, so if you have to ditch the vessel you’re on and step up into a life raft, you still have a way (although it is one way) to communicate your location with would be rescuers. EPIRBs have a bigger battery and bigger antenna than PLBs.
PLB (left) vs. EPIRB (right) for size comparison</p>

<p>A PLB is exactly the same thing but miniature and ideally worn by a crew member 24/7.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2182.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>So why do I think it’s foolish to rely solely on a vessels EPIRB? Let me list a few basic reasons:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>When your life is on the line do you want (1) one chance to survive?
When was the last time a piece of technology failed on you?
EPIRBs are mobile and held on the boat with a strap or simple mechanism, they’ve been known to detach unintentionally. There went your one life line.
MH370 - the Malaysian aircraft that went down and the transponder couldn’t be reached before the battery gave out. Hmm 10 oz of weight gets you another 24 hours of beaconing. Imagine if everyone was wearing one. Survival odds go up for those prepared.
It’s $240 bucks and could save your life.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>What a PLB isn’t; it isn’t a guarantee you’ll survive. It also isn’t a protection against falling in the ocean. Your odds of survival even if you had a PLB in 60 degree F water are bad. But I’d rather have a chance, how about you?</p>

<p>Ultimately a PLB is one element of a risk management strategy that has to be used at the right time and situation. There isn’t one golden ticket that’ll save you. Being well prepared mentally and selecting your kit as compensating controls to identified and likely risks is my method. Its the one I’ll practice throughout my team’s adventure across the Pacific Ocean by ocean rowing boat.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="rowing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve recently seen some commentary that Personal Locator Beacons (PLB) aren’t needed with Ocean Rowing adventures/ expeditions/ trips.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Food Time: Meal Pattern Repetition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meal-pattern-repetition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food Time: Meal Pattern Repetition" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food-time-meal-pattern-repetition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meal-pattern-repetition/"><![CDATA[This is Part 1 of a series of posts about food for the trip.

Enjoying your favorite foods is amazing. Eating your favorite foods for every meal, every 2 hours, over the course of 7 weeks, is a surefire way to change favorite to repulsive.

So that's where we start with meal planning. Freeze dried foods (what I'm bringing) aren't anyone's favorite foods to begin with so it's an uphill battle.  In addition to just flavor, there's so many different challenges to overcome from ensuring nutritional requirements, keeping a healthy stomach, to enjoying the meal. 

Let's start with a few assumptions:

Variety of meals is essential
Simplicity is king
Build in resiliency for spoilage, packaging issues, etc.
5 meals per day
45 day schedule for meals
My first iteration of a meal plan only had one vendor and 6 meal options.  Knowing i'll eat 5 meals per day and that I only like 5 of the options, 5 flavors only gives me variety within the day (Turkey for breakfast one day; for lunch the next). But it doesn't give me any variety across days or weeks. 

Example 1: (Variety within the day but not across days) 

Day 1 : ABCDE

Day 2: EDCBA

So I investigated adding in another vendor to the mix. Adding in just a few more meal types, increases the variety over multiple days while still staying simple. 

Example 2: (Variety added in with the inclusion of just 1 more meal flavor) (Meal F)

Day 1: ABCDE

Day 2: FABCD

Day 3: EFABC

Noticing that the second vendor has more than 1 flavor, means with little extra work here on land, I can greatly increase the variety with zero increase in complexity while on the water. Also this strategy lends itself to hedging against failed packaging and spoilage by adding in a second vendor's packaging process. 

Let's say at this point, I took the idea of adding in the second vendor's food to increase my variety to heart. I went wild with adding in additional meals and ended up with the picture below. 
![1st Vendor Food Options with Grid](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_pattern_repitition..png)

I continue with this idea of adding in variety within each vendor and layering additional variety using both together. Keep reading about meal planning in Part 2.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Part 1 of a series of posts about food for the trip. Enjoying your favorite foods is amazing. Eating your favorite foods for every meal, every 2 hours, over the course of 7 weeks, is a surefire way to change favorite to repulsive. So that’s where we start with meal planning. Freeze dried foods (what I’m bringing) aren’t anyone’s favorite foods to begin with so it’s an uphill battle. In addition to just flavor, there’s so many different challenges to overcome from ensuring nutritional requirements, keeping a healthy stomach, to enjoying the meal. Let’s start with a few assumptions: Variety of meals is essential Simplicity is king Build in resiliency for spoilage, packaging issues, etc. 5 meals per day 45 day schedule for meals My first iteration of a meal plan only had one vendor and 6 meal options. Knowing i’ll eat 5 meals per day and that I only like 5 of the options, 5 flavors only gives me variety within the day (Turkey for breakfast one day; for lunch the next). But it doesn’t give me any variety across days or weeks. Example 1: (Variety within the day but not across days) Day 1 : ABCDE Day 2: EDCBA So I investigated adding in another vendor to the mix. Adding in just a few more meal types, increases the variety over multiple days while still staying simple. Example 2: (Variety added in with the inclusion of just 1 more meal flavor) (Meal F) Day 1: ABCDE Day 2: FABCD Day 3: EFABC Noticing that the second vendor has more than 1 flavor, means with little extra work here on land, I can greatly increase the variety with zero increase in complexity while on the water. Also this strategy lends itself to hedging against failed packaging and spoilage by adding in a second vendor’s packaging process. Let’s say at this point, I took the idea of adding in the second vendor’s food to increase my variety to heart. I went wild with adding in additional meals and ended up with the picture below. I continue with this idea of adding in variety within each vendor and layering additional variety using both together. Keep reading about meal planning in Part 2.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liquid Lunch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liquid Lunch" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch.html"><![CDATA[The overall meal plan for the trip is 6000 calories per rower per day. This consists of a meal plan built around 5 meals of 800 calories. Read more about my meal plan, here.

But that's only 4000 calories. We still need to consume an additional 2000 calories daily. 

A previous ocean rower once told me that he was tired of chewing with the required amount of food that you must take in. Taking that advice and knowing that we can find liquids (+ powder) to supplement a good portion of calories is the plan. 

At the moment I believe I can find about 1000 calories in liquid snacks. This would leave 1000 calories to be found though snack bars but let's see how far we can get with liquids. 

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/basic_liquid_plan.png)
Here's a plan to have 5 servings a day of liquid snack over the entire trip. 

Some basic math gives us the above chart and breaks it down into the below calorie requirement. 

1000 calories / 5 servings = 200 calories per serving 

Why 5 servings? I did the math a few times with 4 servings and 6 servings as guesses and 200 calories seems about right for what i can find food wise. 

From this chart we can also see that 225 servings will be needed to make the trip for 45 days. 

In the below picture I tried out a number of different scenarios to see what options might exist for using expensive powders vs. less expensive powders then changing the number and frequency of servings to offset cost. This model didn't work out as well as I had hoped. Also it would complex to implement while at sea. 

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/complex_liquid_plan.png)

The above picture while too complex for me, might work for others. However collapsing Liquid B and Liquid C into a single item might give variety (2 options vs. 1) . 

My current thinking is to use 2 options. Switching to a view of the pricing and servings can inform us on what I've found for filling the two spots.

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/liquid_prices.png)

In the above worksheet picture, 225 servings are broken down into two options, Milk Powder + Protein and Recovery (carb + protein) powder. 

I based this off of price per calorie. I have done separate research as far as the quality of the calories and the nutrients that make up each supplement. 

On the right side of the sheet there is a 'number of boxes to order' which shows how many boxes/tubs are needed to make the 45 day trip when consuming 5 servings per day based on the manufactures serving size. I've also rounded up on boxes required. 

So ultimately, my plan is to work between the two liquid calorie supplements based on the diagram above (collapsing the B & C liquids into one). I'll purchase the required amount of each supplement and ration them out with the included scoop. I won't be individually packaging the powders into daily allotments.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The overall meal plan for the trip is 6000 calories per rower per day. This consists of a meal plan built around 5 meals of 800 calories. Read more about my meal plan, here. But that’s only 4000 calories. We still need to consume an additional 2000 calories daily. A previous ocean rower once told me that he was tired of chewing with the required amount of food that you must take in. Taking that advice and knowing that we can find liquids (+ powder) to supplement a good portion of calories is the plan. At the moment I believe I can find about 1000 calories in liquid snacks. This would leave 1000 calories to be found though snack bars but let’s see how far we can get with liquids. Here’s a plan to have 5 servings a day of liquid snack over the entire trip. Some basic math gives us the above chart and breaks it down into the below calorie requirement. 1000 calories / 5 servings = 200 calories per serving Why 5 servings? I did the math a few times with 4 servings and 6 servings as guesses and 200 calories seems about right for what i can find food wise. From this chart we can also see that 225 servings will be needed to make the trip for 45 days. In the below picture I tried out a number of different scenarios to see what options might exist for using expensive powders vs. less expensive powders then changing the number and frequency of servings to offset cost. This model didn’t work out as well as I had hoped. Also it would complex to implement while at sea. The above picture while too complex for me, might work for others. However collapsing Liquid B and Liquid C into a single item might give variety (2 options vs. 1) . My current thinking is to use 2 options. Switching to a view of the pricing and servings can inform us on what I’ve found for filling the two spots. In the above worksheet picture, 225 servings are broken down into two options, Milk Powder + Protein and Recovery (carb + protein) powder. I based this off of price per calorie. I have done separate research as far as the quality of the calories and the nutrients that make up each supplement. On the right side of the sheet there is a ‘number of boxes to order’ which shows how many boxes/tubs are needed to make the 45 day trip when consuming 5 servings per day based on the manufactures serving size. I’ve also rounded up on boxes required. So ultimately, my plan is to work between the two liquid calorie supplements based on the diagram above (collapsing the B &amp; C liquids into one). I’ll purchase the required amount of each supplement and ration them out with the included scoop. I won’t be individually packaging the powders into daily allotments.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meal Pattern Repetition: Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meal Pattern Repetition: Part 2" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2.html"><![CDATA[This is Part 2 of Meal Pattern Repetition. See [Part 1](/meal-pattern-repetition/) for the beginning.

   This is a two part process as I am working with 2 vendors. We'll first go through how I added in variety within the first vendor (5 options) then how I layered the second vendor's options on top of the initial strategy. 

FYI, An alphabetical letter has been designated to each meal type. Similar to the examples in Part 1 but in grid format. 
![1st Vendor Food Options with Grid](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_pattern_repitition..png)


In Image 1, notice only 4 meals are entered for each day. I decided to include one meal from the second vendor each day. This was done because with 5 options as shown in Part 1, Example 1, meal variety over days didn't exist. This is also true over weeks with adding in only 1 meal from the second vendor. 

However, moving to 4 meal from vendor 1, gives me more variety within the day and week. Adding in the second vendor gives variety over weeks. 

Next, seeing the patterns, represented by the blue and red brackets, shows that similar meal patterns exist every 6 days. Knowing that we'll be out there for weeks, I wanted to improve upon this. 

In the Image, day 4, 8, 12, 16, N+4  will be populated by the second vendor's food entirely. This will give a break to the red/blue cycle and allow me to use even more variety.

This next image is what I call, the Nested Diagram, it shows the meals provided by both vendors. As this was a template for my own planning, I switched to using '1's to note a meal without regard to vendor. As a side note the 45th day's second to last meal breaks the pattern. This was a product of ordering a even number from the second vendor.

For meal planning patterns this is where i'm at currently. Look for a future post on further food selection including snacks. I'll also post up on how we're going to bag each day's rations once the food arrives. 
![Nested Diagram](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_vendors_nesting.png)
Image: Nested Diagram
Image: 

In the end i believe the meal plan as shown above provides:

a simple meal plan each day (grab a meal and eat from the daily bag)
a simple plan over the course of weeks (build it while you're well rested and on land)
a hedge against one vendor having a spoiled meal (packaging issue, placement in boat, etc.)
variety of meals for nutrition and flavor
Not a requirement but there's a modicum of cost optimization by using meals of different prices
Food Time
Comment]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Part 2 of Meal Pattern Repetition. See Part 1 for the beginning. This is a two part process as I am working with 2 vendors. We’ll first go through how I added in variety within the first vendor (5 options) then how I layered the second vendor’s options on top of the initial strategy. FYI, An alphabetical letter has been designated to each meal type. Similar to the examples in Part 1 but in grid format. In Image 1, notice only 4 meals are entered for each day. I decided to include one meal from the second vendor each day. This was done because with 5 options as shown in Part 1, Example 1, meal variety over days didn’t exist. This is also true over weeks with adding in only 1 meal from the second vendor. However, moving to 4 meal from vendor 1, gives me more variety within the day and week. Adding in the second vendor gives variety over weeks. Next, seeing the patterns, represented by the blue and red brackets, shows that similar meal patterns exist every 6 days. Knowing that we’ll be out there for weeks, I wanted to improve upon this. In the Image, day 4, 8, 12, 16, N+4 will be populated by the second vendor’s food entirely. This will give a break to the red/blue cycle and allow me to use even more variety. This next image is what I call, the Nested Diagram, it shows the meals provided by both vendors. As this was a template for my own planning, I switched to using ‘1’s to note a meal without regard to vendor. As a side note the 45th day’s second to last meal breaks the pattern. This was a product of ordering a even number from the second vendor. For meal planning patterns this is where i’m at currently. Look for a future post on further food selection including snacks. I’ll also post up on how we’re going to bag each day’s rations once the food arrives. Image: Nested Diagram Image: In the end i believe the meal plan as shown above provides: a simple meal plan each day (grab a meal and eat from the daily bag) a simple plan over the course of weeks (build it while you’re well rested and on land) a hedge against one vendor having a spoiled meal (packaging issue, placement in boat, etc.) variety of meals for nutrition and flavor Not a requirement but there’s a modicum of cost optimization by using meals of different prices Food Time Comment]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A blog reboot in earnest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A blog reboot in earnest" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot.html"><![CDATA[<p>I hadn’t really put any time into blogging or posting what’s been going on since the beginning of this crazy adventure. But I think i’m turning a corner on ‘why’ I should do this. I need to share back what I’ve learned as this sport/?activity? is in the dark ages compared to just about anything else out there.</p>

<p>I’ve also been crazy busy trying to wrangle together everything i need to do before my flight out to Monterey in May. One way to track that is through posts. :)</p>

<p>Here’s a quick excerpt off the top of my head</p>
<ul>
    <li> Finish my will  </li>
    <li> Buy a different kind of diaper rash cream based on a coworker's suggestion  </li>
    <li> Finish my 75 kilometers of erg'ing meters for the week   </li>
    <li> Send my food supplier my meal list! (Over $2000 in meals not including snacks) </li>
    <li> Send out sponsorship letters for a few remaining items</li>
</ul>

<p>Two notes for today, my 15k erg piece wasn’t fun. The time does go by quickly for the most part but once you notice time, everything slows down. Second note, my new Zhik 160 dinghy boots haven’t needed any breaking in for use with the erg and they feel great even at the end of a piece.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hadn’t really put any time into blogging or posting what’s been going on since the beginning of this crazy adventure. But I think i’m turning a corner on ‘why’ I should do this. I need to share back what I’ve learned as this sport/?activity? is in the dark ages compared to just about anything else out there. I’ve also been crazy busy trying to wrangle together everything i need to do before my flight out to Monterey in May. One way to track that is through posts. :) Here’s a quick excerpt off the top of my head Finish my will Buy a different kind of diaper rash cream based on a coworker's suggestion Finish my 75 kilometers of erg'ing meters for the week Send my food supplier my meal list! (Over $2000 in meals not including snacks) Send out sponsorship letters for a few remaining items Two notes for today, my 15k erg piece wasn’t fun. The time does go by quickly for the most part but once you notice time, everything slows down. Second note, my new Zhik 160 dinghy boots haven’t needed any breaking in for use with the erg and they feel great even at the end of a piece.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Foul Weather Jackets - First Observations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/18/foul-weather-jackets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Foul Weather Jackets - First Observations" /><published>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/18/foul-weather-jackets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/18/foul-weather-jackets.html"><![CDATA[![zhik-jackets](/assets/images/foul-weather-gear/zhik-jackets.png)

While we all want to look like a Volvo Ocean racer wearing the most high tech foul weather gear, do ocean rowers need it?

I went to the Annapolis SailBoat Show to find out how extreme we need to go, to get the right gear. In the process, I learned alot about the features, models, and sizing differences. In this post I'll give an overview on the jackets that were on offer and my opinion.

Walking into the show I had a very short list of requirements for foul weather gear. 

Material, seams, and surface waterproofing should last at least 50 days on the Pacific Ocean.
Jacket weight should be comparable to competitors offering 
Getting in and out of the garments should not take any thought
Garment should give range of motion that is near equal to rowing motion without jacket and pants.
The vendors and the models that were looked at or referenced:

-Musto: HPX and MPX 
-Zhik: Isotak 2 Ocean and Race
-Gill: Ocean Racer and OS1
-Henri Lloyd: Off shore Elite and Pro
-Helly Hansen: Aegir Race and Ocean

Observations:

One of the first things that I found out was the difference in the cut between brands is pretty close in the Medium/ Large jacket. At six feet tall and 175 lbs. I was tight in the Medium jacket and far more comfortable in the Large across all brands. Zhik's Isotak 2 was the only jacket I would feel comfortable wearing as a Medium. But I would still go for a Large, if I was to buy this jacket as layering underneath could make the fit tighter. 

Some of the brands offered trim versions of their jackets compared to the 'Pro' or 'Ocean' version. As there won't be much room for moving about, having a more fitted and trim jacket would help. The price also seems to be less for the non Pro/ Ocean versions. The reduction in size seemed to be in the torso not in the bicep or raising the arm holes. 

Stretching and simulating rowing in all the jackets was easy. The sleeve length was longer than I expected but welcome as reach in a rowing garment is essential. I wear a 33/34 inch sleeve in dress shirts and all the jackets had sleeves that went past my thumb with arms straight down. 

 The long tail of the jackets was also welcome for rowing. However, i'm not convinced that the jacket length's are in the sweet spot where we wouldn't be sitting on it, caught in tracks, nor it flaring out while on recovery phase of the stroke. 

I would note that the most extreme versions of the jackets tended to be exceptionally long and on small rowing boats likely excessive. This included Helly Hansen Aegir Ocean and Musto HPX Pro.

Jacket weight. 
Effectiveness of every ounce added to the jacket is hard for a non quantitative approach but I can at least note the two extremes in weight. Musto's HPX was the heaviest and Zhik's Isotak 2 (non ocean) was the lightest. Helly Hansen and Henri Lloyd were heavier but in the 'marina' with Zhik. Gill's jacket struck me as a typical heavy winter coat weight but was still lighter than Musto's. 

A noticeable difference between the top two tiers of each company was the robustness of the exterior material used. I have no doubt that months on the sea would be attainable with the each brand's top tier jacket. Its a hard call on which tier to go with unless they both have the top tier material just in different quantities.  

Pockets, hoods, reinforcements. Although each of these are important they seemed to be fairly represented across all the lines without one being notably better than the rest. Reinforcement was provided on elbows and on the seat, so no differentiation could be made.  

How can we differentiate between the products to make a decision? I think the easier criteria revolves around price and availability. There's likely more feature differences in the pants than in the jacket.

Price could be skewed with athletic sponsorship, whether in kind donations of gear or discounts. But outside of that large factor, the price of the jackets ranged from $600 USD to $1000 USD. 

During the boatshow, many of the vendors mentioned they are releasing new versions early next year, so fit and availability of the existing models might be hit or miss depending on timing. 

Ultimately the trip to the boatshow was worth the time for me. While one jacket didn't stand out, I have a reasonable comfort now that all the jackets could meet my unscientific requirements.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While we all want to look like a Volvo Ocean racer wearing the most high tech foul weather gear, do ocean rowers need it? I went to the Annapolis SailBoat Show to find out how extreme we need to go, to get the right gear. In the process, I learned alot about the features, models, and sizing differences. In this post I’ll give an overview on the jackets that were on offer and my opinion. Walking into the show I had a very short list of requirements for foul weather gear. Material, seams, and surface waterproofing should last at least 50 days on the Pacific Ocean. Jacket weight should be comparable to competitors offering Getting in and out of the garments should not take any thought Garment should give range of motion that is near equal to rowing motion without jacket and pants. The vendors and the models that were looked at or referenced: -Musto: HPX and MPX -Zhik: Isotak 2 Ocean and Race -Gill: Ocean Racer and OS1 -Henri Lloyd: Off shore Elite and Pro -Helly Hansen: Aegir Race and Ocean Observations: One of the first things that I found out was the difference in the cut between brands is pretty close in the Medium/ Large jacket. At six feet tall and 175 lbs. I was tight in the Medium jacket and far more comfortable in the Large across all brands. Zhik’s Isotak 2 was the only jacket I would feel comfortable wearing as a Medium. But I would still go for a Large, if I was to buy this jacket as layering underneath could make the fit tighter. Some of the brands offered trim versions of their jackets compared to the ‘Pro’ or ‘Ocean’ version. As there won’t be much room for moving about, having a more fitted and trim jacket would help. The price also seems to be less for the non Pro/ Ocean versions. The reduction in size seemed to be in the torso not in the bicep or raising the arm holes. Stretching and simulating rowing in all the jackets was easy. The sleeve length was longer than I expected but welcome as reach in a rowing garment is essential. I wear a 33/34 inch sleeve in dress shirts and all the jackets had sleeves that went past my thumb with arms straight down. The long tail of the jackets was also welcome for rowing. However, i’m not convinced that the jacket length’s are in the sweet spot where we wouldn’t be sitting on it, caught in tracks, nor it flaring out while on recovery phase of the stroke. I would note that the most extreme versions of the jackets tended to be exceptionally long and on small rowing boats likely excessive. This included Helly Hansen Aegir Ocean and Musto HPX Pro. Jacket weight. Effectiveness of every ounce added to the jacket is hard for a non quantitative approach but I can at least note the two extremes in weight. Musto’s HPX was the heaviest and Zhik’s Isotak 2 (non ocean) was the lightest. Helly Hansen and Henri Lloyd were heavier but in the ‘marina’ with Zhik. Gill’s jacket struck me as a typical heavy winter coat weight but was still lighter than Musto’s. A noticeable difference between the top two tiers of each company was the robustness of the exterior material used. I have no doubt that months on the sea would be attainable with the each brand’s top tier jacket. Its a hard call on which tier to go with unless they both have the top tier material just in different quantities. Pockets, hoods, reinforcements. Although each of these are important they seemed to be fairly represented across all the lines without one being notably better than the rest. Reinforcement was provided on elbows and on the seat, so no differentiation could be made. How can we differentiate between the products to make a decision? I think the easier criteria revolves around price and availability. There’s likely more feature differences in the pants than in the jacket. Price could be skewed with athletic sponsorship, whether in kind donations of gear or discounts. But outside of that large factor, the price of the jackets ranged from $600 USD to $1000 USD. During the boatshow, many of the vendors mentioned they are releasing new versions early next year, so fit and availability of the existing models might be hit or miss depending on timing. Ultimately the trip to the boatshow was worth the time for me. While one jacket didn’t stand out, I have a reasonable comfort now that all the jackets could meet my unscientific requirements.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ocean Rowing Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/02/01/the-basics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ocean Rowing Basics" /><published>2018-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/02/01/the-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/02/01/the-basics.html"><![CDATA[The Basics
Ocean rowing information seems as hard to find as the training is to do. Exhaustive searching day in and out for loosely associated information seems to be the norm. Here's my attempt at relieving some of the research burden and making the information a bit more accessible

Quick Navigation:

Diet | Food | Rowing | Erg | Erg Training | Gear | Notable Ocean Rowers
![food options](/assets/images/basics/food_options.png)

Diet and Body Weight Preparations
My diet during the row will be made up of freeze dried meals (like above), snack bars, carb/protein powders, and supplements (arthritis, skin, basic vitamin, joint). 

A quick break down of calories:

4000 calories - 5 x 800 calorie Freeze dried meals
1000 calories - 5 x 200 calorie Liquid snacks
1000 calories 5 x 200 calorie Solid snacks
Total ~ 6000 calories per day!
The average ocean rower will lose 15-20 lbs over the course of an ocean crossing. This is about 10% body weight for most rowers (not just body fat). 

Over the past year I've gained 20+ pounds to make sure I'm still a healthy weight by the end of the trip.
Summer 2017 weight 165 lbs ; weight as of (April 2018) 187 lbs. The weight gain is comprised of 50% body fat increase and 50% muscle increase. 
Food Details:
In addition to the detail provided here, I've written multiple blog posts about food planning. Check out the blog, here.

The freeze dried meals are 800 calorie meals, and we'll be eating 5 of them a day over the course of the entire adventure. These meals come in a variety of flavors including:

<p><small>Lentils and Rice with Curry</small></p>
<p><small>Black beans and rice with cheese and bell peppers </small></p>
<p><small>Rice with spicy sundries tomatoes </small></p>
<p><small>Pasta with red pesto </small></p>
-Oatmeal with flax seeds
For a sense of what a meal looks like dry and cooked, see the pictures below. (*they're all better than you'd expect)

![(dry) Expedition Foods - Spaghetti Bolognese](/assets/images/basics/exped_foods_bolognese_dry.jpeg)

(dry) Expedition Foods - Spaghetti Bolognese

![(dry) Expedition Foods - Spaghetti Bolognese](/assets/images/basics/exped_foods_bolognese.jpeg)
(wet/cooked) Organic Expedition Foods - Pasta with Red Pesto
(wet/cooked) Organic Expedition Foods - Pasta with Red Pesto

Liquid Snacks
The remaining 2000 calories are broken up between liquid snacks and bar snacks. 

Liquid snacks for this trip consist of 2 different options:

Milk powder + flavored protein
Carb/Protein after workout recovery powder 
We will be consuming a liquid snack 5 times a day consisting of ~180-200 calories per serving. Drinking some of the calories will cut down on the amount of chewing required to consume 6000 calories and will encourage hydration as water is required for mixing both drinks.

Solid Snacks
Bar snacks aren't your typical bar snacks (peanuts and pretzels), but they're not far off. We will be consuming these snacks at the same interval and size as the liquid snacks. 5 servings, 200 calories each serving. 

These snacks are made up of:

Peanut butter spreads (~1oz pouches)
Meal replacement bars (super food bars, different flavors)
How do you learn and train for this type of rowing?
I started with a local 'learn to row' class at Hampton Roads Rowing Club (HRRC) in Norfolk, VA. When I moved to Richmond, VA, I joined the local rowing club, Virginia Boat Club (VBC). Below is a clip of a typical day of rowing in the summer. I'm on the far right of the video in the white shirt. Typical workout is 10-15kms.

Also check out my page on Endurance Rowing.


During the winter and any time you can't go out (storms, river is at flood stage, debris coming down river) you would row on an ergometer (an 'erg' for short).

My normal workout is a 15km continuous row at 2:00 per 500 meters limiting myself to a max of 16 strokes per minute. 

Example workout summary from a erg
Example workout summary from a erg

Early 2018, getting my meters in alone in the boathouse.
Early 2018, getting my meters in alone in the boathouse. 

Joining a rowing club is far from the only way to become an ocean rower. Many other disciplines can bring much needed skill sets to the table and prove to be as valuable as knowing proper rowing form. Some other examples would be sailing, mountain climbing and other expedition sports, or even project management. Having great project management skills makes this multi discipline type of event much easier than just knowing how to row hard.

Sponsorship Materials

Here's the PDF used by the team to work with sponsors

[Team Uniting Nations Sponsorship Package](/assets/files/UnitingNationsSponsorshipPack0927.pdf)

![](/assets/images/basics/trio.png)]]></content><author><name>Robert</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Basics Ocean rowing information seems as hard to find as the training is to do. Exhaustive searching day in and out for loosely associated information seems to be the norm. Here’s my attempt at relieving some of the research burden and making the information a bit more accessible Quick Navigation: Diet | Food | Rowing | Erg | Erg Training | Gear | Notable Ocean Rowers Diet and Body Weight Preparations My diet during the row will be made up of freeze dried meals (like above), snack bars, carb/protein powders, and supplements (arthritis, skin, basic vitamin, joint). A quick break down of calories: 4000 calories - 5 x 800 calorie Freeze dried meals 1000 calories - 5 x 200 calorie Liquid snacks 1000 calories 5 x 200 calorie Solid snacks Total ~ 6000 calories per day! The average ocean rower will lose 15-20 lbs over the course of an ocean crossing. This is about 10% body weight for most rowers (not just body fat). Over the past year I’ve gained 20+ pounds to make sure I’m still a healthy weight by the end of the trip. Summer 2017 weight 165 lbs ; weight as of (April 2018) 187 lbs. The weight gain is comprised of 50% body fat increase and 50% muscle increase. Food Details: In addition to the detail provided here, I’ve written multiple blog posts about food planning. Check out the blog, here. The freeze dried meals are 800 calorie meals, and we’ll be eating 5 of them a day over the course of the entire adventure. These meals come in a variety of flavors including: Lentils and Rice with Curry Black beans and rice with cheese and bell peppers Rice with spicy sundries tomatoes Pasta with red pesto -Oatmeal with flax seeds For a sense of what a meal looks like dry and cooked, see the pictures below. (*they’re all better than you’d expect) (dry) Expedition Foods - Spaghetti Bolognese (wet/cooked) Organic Expedition Foods - Pasta with Red Pesto (wet/cooked) Organic Expedition Foods - Pasta with Red Pesto Liquid Snacks The remaining 2000 calories are broken up between liquid snacks and bar snacks. Liquid snacks for this trip consist of 2 different options: Milk powder + flavored protein Carb/Protein after workout recovery powder We will be consuming a liquid snack 5 times a day consisting of ~180-200 calories per serving. Drinking some of the calories will cut down on the amount of chewing required to consume 6000 calories and will encourage hydration as water is required for mixing both drinks. Solid Snacks Bar snacks aren’t your typical bar snacks (peanuts and pretzels), but they’re not far off. We will be consuming these snacks at the same interval and size as the liquid snacks. 5 servings, 200 calories each serving. These snacks are made up of: Peanut butter spreads (~1oz pouches) Meal replacement bars (super food bars, different flavors) How do you learn and train for this type of rowing? I started with a local ‘learn to row’ class at Hampton Roads Rowing Club (HRRC) in Norfolk, VA. When I moved to Richmond, VA, I joined the local rowing club, Virginia Boat Club (VBC). Below is a clip of a typical day of rowing in the summer. I’m on the far right of the video in the white shirt. Typical workout is 10-15kms. Also check out my page on Endurance Rowing. During the winter and any time you can’t go out (storms, river is at flood stage, debris coming down river) you would row on an ergometer (an ‘erg’ for short). My normal workout is a 15km continuous row at 2:00 per 500 meters limiting myself to a max of 16 strokes per minute. Example workout summary from a erg Example workout summary from a erg Early 2018, getting my meters in alone in the boathouse. Early 2018, getting my meters in alone in the boathouse. Joining a rowing club is far from the only way to become an ocean rower. Many other disciplines can bring much needed skill sets to the table and prove to be as valuable as knowing proper rowing form. Some other examples would be sailing, mountain climbing and other expedition sports, or even project management. Having great project management skills makes this multi discipline type of event much easier than just knowing how to row hard. Sponsorship Materials Here’s the PDF used by the team to work with sponsors Team Uniting Nations Sponsorship Package]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Swimming in Annapolis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/10/12/swimming-in-annapolis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Swimming in Annapolis" /><published>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/10/12/swimming-in-annapolis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/10/12/swimming-in-annapolis.html"><![CDATA[![Thistle fleet](/assets/images/swimming-annapolis/Thistle-2-580.jpg)

TLDR; Went dinghy racing, capsized a few times and have the bruises to prove it. Whether kaleidoscope colored bruises or just a bruised ego, i'm still charging ahead with sailing and the Pacific ocean row. 

Labor day weekend was an exciting and slightly painful weekend. I raced in my first sailing regatta with the Severn Sailing Association, the Thistle Crab Regatta. Meghan and I packed up early that morning for our trip to Annapolis, MD with all my water proof gear in tow. From my SealLine Nimbus dry bag, waterproof jacket, and pants. Not much but its all I had. And we knew it was going to be a wet day, although I didn't exactly know how wet. On a personal prideful note, my Vespoli rowing neoprene booties were very out of place acting as 'water resistant' socks but they were a welcome addition compared to a basic cotton sock. 

Well after we arrived, the sun rising, and meeting up with the crew, I attended the captains meeting with Bill, the boat captain. The group decision was to go ahead with the races although in the harbor vs. out further, due to the incoming weather system, a slightly telling note for my first race. We next loaded the boat, put it in the water and headed out in the light breeze but spitting rain. Fortunately, the rain felt like it was coming from behind us and I was quite warm and happy in my waterproof gear. Although it wasn't going to be a hot lunch, knowing that my lunch and personal belongings were secured away in the dry bag made me a bit more reassured. 

A salt water logged and soggy PB&J sounds miserable.

Racing sail boats is definitely a new experience to me and my learning curve was especially hard with the new environment, close proximity to other boats, crew I had just met, and the wet surfaces in the boat. My footing gave out numerous times crossing the boat during a tack and like a novice, I went flying about the boat haphazardly. 

My job for the day was sitting midship, controlling the jib lines and hiking out when needed. I thought things were going well. And at first they were. 

From the starting line to the first tack we were in the lead group with a good point, a full sail, and room to move. Through the first tack we were ok, i stumbled a bit crossing sides over the large centerboard and low boom releasing the jib sheet from it's lee side cleat and pulling in on the windward side while starting to hike out to steady the boat back to its belly. Things move much faster during a race than they do on a Sunday practice cruise. While athleticism and spunk provide a great start, there's little substitution for experience. 

Being a bit shocked at the speed and haste at which a tack is committed in a small dinghy, I prepped myself for the next tack and to move just a bit quicker. As the racing fleet staged itself in a continuing flow back and forth progressing to the next marker, we collectively tacked to be even with the ley line to ensure we could round the mark without extra unneeded zig zags down the course. It was called out that we were even with the ley line and we were going to do the final tack before aiming for the mark. As the little boat started to turn, the jib line goes slack and a not rehearsed enough dance proceeds to move bodies to the other side of the boat. As the bow transitions through pointing into the wind, the air rushes into the now slack sail and fills it quickly. However, unlike the last few tacks and in my earnest attempt to do better, I caught the lee side cleat with the jib sheet while also pulling on windward high side. 

Something I've always known, fighting with yourself isn't productive and in this situation, it results in being cold and wet. 

Just as the with the main sail, the jib sheet filled with air and as it was pulled taught on the low side, pulled the boat and mast towards the waves. No one else in the boat expecting me to screw up something so simple, was bracing for the sudden jolt, and the tiller slipped from the captain's hands. The tiller being pushed away acts as a lever to the stern and digs the bow into the waves. A partial capsized boat results and as all hands scramble to release the jib sheet, the captain for the tiller, the mainsheet slaps down onto the waves and we're swimming. 

I'm first over the gunnel to the high side of the boat and sliding down on to the centerboard to apply weight to right the boat. Although the re-righting of a boat had been explained during my intro to sailing class, I had never done it. Waiting for the other two crew to come join me, I held on and bide the seconds that seemed to be moving much slower. 

As I stood there trying to figure out, what the heck just happened, my lunch in its partially air filled dry bag appeared, floating across the main sail, away from me. My only thought was, well there goes my lunch. It was a bit of resigned fate as I couldn't leave the boat in its current state nor the crew that was steadily coming to help stand on the centerboard. As another body joined pressing up from the water, the sail moved and the lunch sack floated just slightly further away. On the wet surface as a third member joined us, I slipped and fell in again, which knocked any thought of lunch out of my mind. 

Once I joined the crew on the centerboard, the boat started to rise and we clambered aboard. Luckily by that point, a safety boat had joined us and we started to bail water out one gallon full bucket at a time. It didn't help the waves and rain were steadily adding to our work.  Fortunately at some point, while fully engaged on the idea of regaining control of the boat, my lunch was rescued by the safety boat. I learned many valuable lessons, first or second to not cleat the jib sheet during a tack and leash your lunch to the boat.

The first race for all its promise turned into a DNF. We however regained a small amount of pride by coming in fourth for the second race even after going for a swim. Trial by capsizing is a pretty swift way of learning, it turns out. But on this day it wasn't enough of a learning curve as in the third race of the day, we capsized the boat again. This time we know it wasn't due to the jib sheet being cleated but there was a bit of confusion exactly what happened. 

After all the racing, the safety team returned my lunch once back on land. Lunch wasn't eaten until hours later when the boat had been washed, returned to its trailer, and the sails packed away. While PB&J wasn't exactly the best lunch, it was a welcomed meal.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="rowing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TLDR; Went dinghy racing, capsized a few times and have the bruises to prove it. Whether kaleidoscope colored bruises or just a bruised ego, i’m still charging ahead with sailing and the Pacific ocean row. Labor day weekend was an exciting and slightly painful weekend. I raced in my first sailing regatta with the Severn Sailing Association, the Thistle Crab Regatta. Meghan and I packed up early that morning for our trip to Annapolis, MD with all my water proof gear in tow. From my SealLine Nimbus dry bag, waterproof jacket, and pants. Not much but its all I had. And we knew it was going to be a wet day, although I didn’t exactly know how wet. On a personal prideful note, my Vespoli rowing neoprene booties were very out of place acting as ‘water resistant’ socks but they were a welcome addition compared to a basic cotton sock. Well after we arrived, the sun rising, and meeting up with the crew, I attended the captains meeting with Bill, the boat captain. The group decision was to go ahead with the races although in the harbor vs. out further, due to the incoming weather system, a slightly telling note for my first race. We next loaded the boat, put it in the water and headed out in the light breeze but spitting rain. Fortunately, the rain felt like it was coming from behind us and I was quite warm and happy in my waterproof gear. Although it wasn’t going to be a hot lunch, knowing that my lunch and personal belongings were secured away in the dry bag made me a bit more reassured. A salt water logged and soggy PB&amp;J sounds miserable. Racing sail boats is definitely a new experience to me and my learning curve was especially hard with the new environment, close proximity to other boats, crew I had just met, and the wet surfaces in the boat. My footing gave out numerous times crossing the boat during a tack and like a novice, I went flying about the boat haphazardly. My job for the day was sitting midship, controlling the jib lines and hiking out when needed. I thought things were going well. And at first they were. From the starting line to the first tack we were in the lead group with a good point, a full sail, and room to move. Through the first tack we were ok, i stumbled a bit crossing sides over the large centerboard and low boom releasing the jib sheet from it’s lee side cleat and pulling in on the windward side while starting to hike out to steady the boat back to its belly. Things move much faster during a race than they do on a Sunday practice cruise. While athleticism and spunk provide a great start, there’s little substitution for experience. Being a bit shocked at the speed and haste at which a tack is committed in a small dinghy, I prepped myself for the next tack and to move just a bit quicker. As the racing fleet staged itself in a continuing flow back and forth progressing to the next marker, we collectively tacked to be even with the ley line to ensure we could round the mark without extra unneeded zig zags down the course. It was called out that we were even with the ley line and we were going to do the final tack before aiming for the mark. As the little boat started to turn, the jib line goes slack and a not rehearsed enough dance proceeds to move bodies to the other side of the boat. As the bow transitions through pointing into the wind, the air rushes into the now slack sail and fills it quickly. However, unlike the last few tacks and in my earnest attempt to do better, I caught the lee side cleat with the jib sheet while also pulling on windward high side. Something I’ve always known, fighting with yourself isn’t productive and in this situation, it results in being cold and wet. Just as the with the main sail, the jib sheet filled with air and as it was pulled taught on the low side, pulled the boat and mast towards the waves. No one else in the boat expecting me to screw up something so simple, was bracing for the sudden jolt, and the tiller slipped from the captain’s hands. The tiller being pushed away acts as a lever to the stern and digs the bow into the waves. A partial capsized boat results and as all hands scramble to release the jib sheet, the captain for the tiller, the mainsheet slaps down onto the waves and we’re swimming. I’m first over the gunnel to the high side of the boat and sliding down on to the centerboard to apply weight to right the boat. Although the re-righting of a boat had been explained during my intro to sailing class, I had never done it. Waiting for the other two crew to come join me, I held on and bide the seconds that seemed to be moving much slower. As I stood there trying to figure out, what the heck just happened, my lunch in its partially air filled dry bag appeared, floating across the main sail, away from me. My only thought was, well there goes my lunch. It was a bit of resigned fate as I couldn’t leave the boat in its current state nor the crew that was steadily coming to help stand on the centerboard. As another body joined pressing up from the water, the sail moved and the lunch sack floated just slightly further away. On the wet surface as a third member joined us, I slipped and fell in again, which knocked any thought of lunch out of my mind. Once I joined the crew on the centerboard, the boat started to rise and we clambered aboard. Luckily by that point, a safety boat had joined us and we started to bail water out one gallon full bucket at a time. It didn’t help the waves and rain were steadily adding to our work. Fortunately at some point, while fully engaged on the idea of regaining control of the boat, my lunch was rescued by the safety boat. I learned many valuable lessons, first or second to not cleat the jib sheet during a tack and leash your lunch to the boat. The first race for all its promise turned into a DNF. We however regained a small amount of pride by coming in fourth for the second race even after going for a swim. Trial by capsizing is a pretty swift way of learning, it turns out. But on this day it wasn’t enough of a learning curve as in the third race of the day, we capsized the boat again. This time we know it wasn’t due to the jib sheet being cleated but there was a bit of confusion exactly what happened. After all the racing, the safety team returned my lunch once back on land. Lunch wasn’t eaten until hours later when the boat had been washed, returned to its trailer, and the sails packed away. While PB&amp;J wasn’t exactly the best lunch, it was a welcomed meal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life became even more busy once the decision was made</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/07/03/life-became-busy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life became even more busy once the decision was made" /><published>2017-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/07/03/life-became-busy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2017/07/03/life-became-busy.html"><![CDATA[It's been a few weeks but i'm still riding high off the thrill of clicking the button to enter the 2018 Great Pacific Race. There's so much to do and only 47 weeks to go.. I've been looking forward to setting off on this journey for longer than I can really remember. 

I started rowing in 2012 with the ultimate dream of rowing an ocean. Not knowing how to accomplish that, I decided to learn how to row at the local rowing club [(Hampton Roads Rowing Club)](http://www.hrrc.net/). Since then it's been a whirl wind of growing up, expanding my limits and keeping my eyes open for the next lesson to learn. I have a feeling there will be combination of all three in the coming year and few months. Stay tuned, lots more coming soon.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="rowing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a few weeks but i’m still riding high off the thrill of clicking the button to enter the 2018 Great Pacific Race. There’s so much to do and only 47 weeks to go.. I’ve been looking forward to setting off on this journey for longer than I can really remember. I started rowing in 2012 with the ultimate dream of rowing an ocean. Not knowing how to accomplish that, I decided to learn how to row at the local rowing club (Hampton Roads Rowing Club). Since then it’s been a whirl wind of growing up, expanding my limits and keeping my eyes open for the next lesson to learn. I have a feeling there will be combination of all three in the coming year and few months. Stay tuned, lots more coming soon.]]></summary></entry></feed>