<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-23T20:16:37-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Robert Behny</title><entry><title type="html">Buying a motor online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/buying-a-motor-online.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buying a motor online" /><published>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/buying-a-motor-online</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/buying-a-motor-online.html"><![CDATA[This was a hard process. Much harder than I expected and is series of big gambles.

online store fronts don’t have in stock the motors they post online. Those motors for the most part are representative of what they carry. I’m not sure what would happen if you just picked one and tossed it in your shopping cart. 
in my situation, when I emailed many different vendors they never responded or generally weren’t helpful to find or buy anything. I hate calling people but that’s what it took to start finding anything in stock.]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a hard process. Much harder than I expected and is series of big gambles. online store fronts don’t have in stock the motors they post online. Those motors for the most part are representative of what they carry. I’m not sure what would happen if you just picked one and tossed it in your shopping cart. in my situation, when I emailed many different vendors they never responded or generally weren’t helpful to find or buy anything. I hate calling people but that’s what it took to start finding anything in stock.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How we got to here</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/how-we-got-to-here.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we got to here" /><published>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/how-we-got-to-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/how-we-got-to-here.html"><![CDATA[The RS has a head gasket failure and finally I have a garage where I can work on it myself.

I’d like the RS to be my drive it because you feel like it but not because you have to car. To me this means not using it as a daily driver but I can daily it, if I want to. I’d like to do a yearly road trip in it and a yearly autox/hpde.

![sti coupe picture](/assets/images/sti-coupe.png)]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RS has a head gasket failure and finally I have a garage where I can work on it myself. I’d like the RS to be my drive it because you feel like it but not because you have to car. To me this means not using it as a daily driver but I can daily it, if I want to. I’d like to do a yearly road trip in it and a yearly autox/hpde.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resume</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/resume.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resume" /><published>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/resume</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/11/23/resume.html"><![CDATA[profile picture

I’m actively pursuing a company that wants to treat their customer’s data with respect
I’m passionate about delivering business focused security leadership. And I’m looking for a company that relentlessly focuses on the needs of their customers. Ensuring data privacy, ease of use, and maintaining a secure compliance environment are crucial to maintaining a trust based relationship with customers.

Together I believe we can differentiate the security experience for our customers, partners, and employees. 

What I’m looking to do:                                                                                                                         • Implementing strategic plans to enhance the company’s technical and organizational security through collaborating with business operations teams to ensure the best fit for solutions. This means delivering industry security frameworks in a thoughtful and human way.                                                                                                                                                     • Hands-on implementation and development of required security solutions.                                                                                                                                                     • Champion a security mindset through mentoring and advising others throughout the company.

Where I’m looking:                                                                                                                                                     Boston or Remote

Roles I’m interested in, are typically titled:                                                                                             • Program Manager          • (Senior) Director of Security

• Head of Security            • Practice Lead

resume(PDF)]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[profile picture I’m actively pursuing a company that wants to treat their customer’s data with respect I’m passionate about delivering business focused security leadership. And I’m looking for a company that relentlessly focuses on the needs of their customers. Ensuring data privacy, ease of use, and maintaining a secure compliance environment are crucial to maintaining a trust based relationship with customers. Together I believe we can differentiate the security experience for our customers, partners, and employees. What I’m looking to do: • Implementing strategic plans to enhance the company’s technical and organizational security through collaborating with business operations teams to ensure the best fit for solutions. This means delivering industry security frameworks in a thoughtful and human way. • Hands-on implementation and development of required security solutions. • Champion a security mindset through mentoring and advising others throughout the company. Where I’m looking: Boston or Remote Roles I’m interested in, are typically titled: • Program Manager • (Senior) Director of Security • Head of Security • Practice Lead resume(PDF)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oil Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/21/oil-analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oil Analysis" /><published>2021-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/21/oil-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/21/oil-analysis.html"><![CDATA[Took a sample of oil today from the sti motor and sending it off for analysis. I’m curious about its life prior to now. Also would like to know about any really bad things (bearing material in oil, etc.) before putting it in the RS. The oil didn’t look bad when it came out but it was used and smelled old. It also had a no name filter on it.

Interesting to me was learning about the coolant lines connected to the oiler cooler. That’s the black line above the exhaust going to the silver cooler under the worn off sticker. It uses a combination of hard lines and hoses to flow coolant to the oil cooler. The hardline will be added to a list of parts waiting to be refurbished.

Side note - I sprayed PBlaster on the heat shielding bolts as I’d like to remove and clean the entire motor up before installing it.]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Took a sample of oil today from the sti motor and sending it off for analysis. I’m curious about its life prior to now. Also would like to know about any really bad things (bearing material in oil, etc.) before putting it in the RS. The oil didn’t look bad when it came out but it was used and smelled old. It also had a no name filter on it. Interesting to me was learning about the coolant lines connected to the oiler cooler. That’s the black line above the exhaust going to the silver cooler under the worn off sticker. It uses a combination of hard lines and hoses to flow coolant to the oil cooler. The hardline will be added to a list of parts waiting to be refurbished. Side note - I sprayed PBlaster on the heat shielding bolts as I’d like to remove and clean the entire motor up before installing it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lost at Sea Why Risk It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lost at Sea Why Risk It" /><published>2018-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/05/13/lost-at-sea-why-risk-it.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2180.png" alt="image" />
I’ve recently seen some commentary that Personal Locator Beacons (PLB) aren’t needed with Ocean Rowing adventures/ expeditions/ trips.</p>

<p>I think that’s a foolish mindset and doesn’t acknowledge the many benefits that this personal device gives you.</p>

<p>Every ocean going vessel should have an Emergency Position Indicating Radio Beacon (EPIRB), a supersized PLB that relays your GPS coordinates and the device ID (which has been registered to a vessel or person with PLBs).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2181.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>What is a EPIRB? <a href="http://www.epirb.com/">Link</a></p>

<p>The idea is that if you’re in grave danger, turning on this device can alert the US Coast Guard or national rescue organization that a situation is unfolding. This device is mobile, so if you have to ditch the vessel you’re on and step up into a life raft, you still have a way (although it is one way) to communicate your location with would be rescuers. EPIRBs have a bigger battery and bigger antenna than PLBs.
PLB (left) vs. EPIRB (right) for size comparison</p>

<p>A PLB is exactly the same thing but miniature and ideally worn by a crew member 24/7.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/lost-at-sea/IMG_2182.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>So why do I think it’s foolish to rely solely on a vessels EPIRB? Let me list a few basic reasons:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>When your life is on the line do you want (1) one chance to survive?
When was the last time a piece of technology failed on you?
EPIRBs are mobile and held on the boat with a strap or simple mechanism, they’ve been known to detach unintentionally. There went your one life line.
MH370 - the Malaysian aircraft that went down and the transponder couldn’t be reached before the battery gave out. Hmm 10 oz of weight gets you another 24 hours of beaconing. Imagine if everyone was wearing one. Survival odds go up for those prepared.
It’s $240 bucks and could save your life.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>What a PLB isn’t; it isn’t a guarantee you’ll survive. It also isn’t a protection against falling in the ocean. Your odds of survival even if you had a PLB in 60 degree F water are bad. But I’d rather have a chance, how about you?</p>

<p>Ultimately a PLB is one element of a risk management strategy that has to be used at the right time and situation. There isn’t one golden ticket that’ll save you. Being well prepared mentally and selecting your kit as compensating controls to identified and likely risks is my method. Its the one I’ll practice throughout my team’s adventure across the Pacific Ocean by ocean rowing boat.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="rowing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve recently seen some commentary that Personal Locator Beacons (PLB) aren’t needed with Ocean Rowing adventures/ expeditions/ trips.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Food Time: Meal Pattern Repetition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meal-pattern-repetition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food Time: Meal Pattern Repetition" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food-time-meal-pattern-repetition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meal-pattern-repetition/"><![CDATA[This is Part 1 of a series of posts about food for the trip.

Enjoying your favorite foods is amazing. Eating your favorite foods for every meal, every 2 hours, over the course of 7 weeks, is a surefire way to change favorite to repulsive.

So that's where we start with meal planning. Freeze dried foods (what I'm bringing) aren't anyone's favorite foods to begin with so it's an uphill battle.  In addition to just flavor, there's so many different challenges to overcome from ensuring nutritional requirements, keeping a healthy stomach, to enjoying the meal. 

Let's start with a few assumptions:

Variety of meals is essential
Simplicity is king
Build in resiliency for spoilage, packaging issues, etc.
5 meals per day
45 day schedule for meals
My first iteration of a meal plan only had one vendor and 6 meal options.  Knowing i'll eat 5 meals per day and that I only like 5 of the options, 5 flavors only gives me variety within the day (Turkey for breakfast one day; for lunch the next). But it doesn't give me any variety across days or weeks. 

Example 1: (Variety within the day but not across days) 

Day 1 : ABCDE

Day 2: EDCBA

So I investigated adding in another vendor to the mix. Adding in just a few more meal types, increases the variety over multiple days while still staying simple. 

Example 2: (Variety added in with the inclusion of just 1 more meal flavor) (Meal F)

Day 1: ABCDE

Day 2: FABCD

Day 3: EFABC

Noticing that the second vendor has more than 1 flavor, means with little extra work here on land, I can greatly increase the variety with zero increase in complexity while on the water. Also this strategy lends itself to hedging against failed packaging and spoilage by adding in a second vendor's packaging process. 

Let's say at this point, I took the idea of adding in the second vendor's food to increase my variety to heart. I went wild with adding in additional meals and ended up with the picture below. 
![1st Vendor Food Options with Grid](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_pattern_repitition..png)

I continue with this idea of adding in variety within each vendor and layering additional variety using both together. Keep reading about meal planning in Part 2.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Part 1 of a series of posts about food for the trip. Enjoying your favorite foods is amazing. Eating your favorite foods for every meal, every 2 hours, over the course of 7 weeks, is a surefire way to change favorite to repulsive. So that’s where we start with meal planning. Freeze dried foods (what I’m bringing) aren’t anyone’s favorite foods to begin with so it’s an uphill battle. In addition to just flavor, there’s so many different challenges to overcome from ensuring nutritional requirements, keeping a healthy stomach, to enjoying the meal. Let’s start with a few assumptions: Variety of meals is essential Simplicity is king Build in resiliency for spoilage, packaging issues, etc. 5 meals per day 45 day schedule for meals My first iteration of a meal plan only had one vendor and 6 meal options. Knowing i’ll eat 5 meals per day and that I only like 5 of the options, 5 flavors only gives me variety within the day (Turkey for breakfast one day; for lunch the next). But it doesn’t give me any variety across days or weeks. Example 1: (Variety within the day but not across days) Day 1 : ABCDE Day 2: EDCBA So I investigated adding in another vendor to the mix. Adding in just a few more meal types, increases the variety over multiple days while still staying simple. Example 2: (Variety added in with the inclusion of just 1 more meal flavor) (Meal F) Day 1: ABCDE Day 2: FABCD Day 3: EFABC Noticing that the second vendor has more than 1 flavor, means with little extra work here on land, I can greatly increase the variety with zero increase in complexity while on the water. Also this strategy lends itself to hedging against failed packaging and spoilage by adding in a second vendor’s packaging process. Let’s say at this point, I took the idea of adding in the second vendor’s food to increase my variety to heart. I went wild with adding in additional meals and ended up with the picture below. I continue with this idea of adding in variety within each vendor and layering additional variety using both together. Keep reading about meal planning in Part 2.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liquid Lunch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liquid Lunch" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/liquid-lunch.html"><![CDATA[The overall meal plan for the trip is 6000 calories per rower per day. This consists of a meal plan built around 5 meals of 800 calories. Read more about my meal plan, here.

But that's only 4000 calories. We still need to consume an additional 2000 calories daily. 

A previous ocean rower once told me that he was tired of chewing with the required amount of food that you must take in. Taking that advice and knowing that we can find liquids (+ powder) to supplement a good portion of calories is the plan. 

At the moment I believe I can find about 1000 calories in liquid snacks. This would leave 1000 calories to be found though snack bars but let's see how far we can get with liquids. 

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/basic_liquid_plan.png)
Here's a plan to have 5 servings a day of liquid snack over the entire trip. 

Some basic math gives us the above chart and breaks it down into the below calorie requirement. 

1000 calories / 5 servings = 200 calories per serving 

Why 5 servings? I did the math a few times with 4 servings and 6 servings as guesses and 200 calories seems about right for what i can find food wise. 

From this chart we can also see that 225 servings will be needed to make the trip for 45 days. 

In the below picture I tried out a number of different scenarios to see what options might exist for using expensive powders vs. less expensive powders then changing the number and frequency of servings to offset cost. This model didn't work out as well as I had hoped. Also it would complex to implement while at sea. 

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/complex_liquid_plan.png)

The above picture while too complex for me, might work for others. However collapsing Liquid B and Liquid C into a single item might give variety (2 options vs. 1) . 

My current thinking is to use 2 options. Switching to a view of the pricing and servings can inform us on what I've found for filling the two spots.

![image](/assets/images/liquid-lunch/liquid_prices.png)

In the above worksheet picture, 225 servings are broken down into two options, Milk Powder + Protein and Recovery (carb + protein) powder. 

I based this off of price per calorie. I have done separate research as far as the quality of the calories and the nutrients that make up each supplement. 

On the right side of the sheet there is a 'number of boxes to order' which shows how many boxes/tubs are needed to make the 45 day trip when consuming 5 servings per day based on the manufactures serving size. I've also rounded up on boxes required. 

So ultimately, my plan is to work between the two liquid calorie supplements based on the diagram above (collapsing the B & C liquids into one). I'll purchase the required amount of each supplement and ration them out with the included scoop. I won't be individually packaging the powders into daily allotments.]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The overall meal plan for the trip is 6000 calories per rower per day. This consists of a meal plan built around 5 meals of 800 calories. Read more about my meal plan, here. But that’s only 4000 calories. We still need to consume an additional 2000 calories daily. A previous ocean rower once told me that he was tired of chewing with the required amount of food that you must take in. Taking that advice and knowing that we can find liquids (+ powder) to supplement a good portion of calories is the plan. At the moment I believe I can find about 1000 calories in liquid snacks. This would leave 1000 calories to be found though snack bars but let’s see how far we can get with liquids. Here’s a plan to have 5 servings a day of liquid snack over the entire trip. Some basic math gives us the above chart and breaks it down into the below calorie requirement. 1000 calories / 5 servings = 200 calories per serving Why 5 servings? I did the math a few times with 4 servings and 6 servings as guesses and 200 calories seems about right for what i can find food wise. From this chart we can also see that 225 servings will be needed to make the trip for 45 days. In the below picture I tried out a number of different scenarios to see what options might exist for using expensive powders vs. less expensive powders then changing the number and frequency of servings to offset cost. This model didn’t work out as well as I had hoped. Also it would complex to implement while at sea. The above picture while too complex for me, might work for others. However collapsing Liquid B and Liquid C into a single item might give variety (2 options vs. 1) . My current thinking is to use 2 options. Switching to a view of the pricing and servings can inform us on what I’ve found for filling the two spots. In the above worksheet picture, 225 servings are broken down into two options, Milk Powder + Protein and Recovery (carb + protein) powder. I based this off of price per calorie. I have done separate research as far as the quality of the calories and the nutrients that make up each supplement. On the right side of the sheet there is a ‘number of boxes to order’ which shows how many boxes/tubs are needed to make the 45 day trip when consuming 5 servings per day based on the manufactures serving size. I’ve also rounded up on boxes required. So ultimately, my plan is to work between the two liquid calorie supplements based on the diagram above (collapsing the B &amp; C liquids into one). I’ll purchase the required amount of each supplement and ration them out with the included scoop. I won’t be individually packaging the powders into daily allotments.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meal Pattern Repetition: Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meal Pattern Repetition: Part 2" /><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/21/meal-repetition-part-2.html"><![CDATA[This is Part 2 of Meal Pattern Repetition. See [Part 1](/meal-pattern-repetition/) for the beginning.

   This is a two part process as I am working with 2 vendors. We'll first go through how I added in variety within the first vendor (5 options) then how I layered the second vendor's options on top of the initial strategy. 

FYI, An alphabetical letter has been designated to each meal type. Similar to the examples in Part 1 but in grid format. 
![1st Vendor Food Options with Grid](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_pattern_repitition..png)


In Image 1, notice only 4 meals are entered for each day. I decided to include one meal from the second vendor each day. This was done because with 5 options as shown in Part 1, Example 1, meal variety over days didn't exist. This is also true over weeks with adding in only 1 meal from the second vendor. 

However, moving to 4 meal from vendor 1, gives me more variety within the day and week. Adding in the second vendor gives variety over weeks. 

Next, seeing the patterns, represented by the blue and red brackets, shows that similar meal patterns exist every 6 days. Knowing that we'll be out there for weeks, I wanted to improve upon this. 

In the Image, day 4, 8, 12, 16, N+4  will be populated by the second vendor's food entirely. This will give a break to the red/blue cycle and allow me to use even more variety.

This next image is what I call, the Nested Diagram, it shows the meals provided by both vendors. As this was a template for my own planning, I switched to using '1's to note a meal without regard to vendor. As a side note the 45th day's second to last meal breaks the pattern. This was a product of ordering a even number from the second vendor.

For meal planning patterns this is where i'm at currently. Look for a future post on further food selection including snacks. I'll also post up on how we're going to bag each day's rations once the food arrives. 
![Nested Diagram](/assets/images/meal-2/meal_vendors_nesting.png)
Image: Nested Diagram
Image: 

In the end i believe the meal plan as shown above provides:

a simple meal plan each day (grab a meal and eat from the daily bag)
a simple plan over the course of weeks (build it while you're well rested and on land)
a hedge against one vendor having a spoiled meal (packaging issue, placement in boat, etc.)
variety of meals for nutrition and flavor
Not a requirement but there's a modicum of cost optimization by using meals of different prices
Food Time
Comment]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Part 2 of Meal Pattern Repetition. See Part 1 for the beginning. This is a two part process as I am working with 2 vendors. We’ll first go through how I added in variety within the first vendor (5 options) then how I layered the second vendor’s options on top of the initial strategy. FYI, An alphabetical letter has been designated to each meal type. Similar to the examples in Part 1 but in grid format. In Image 1, notice only 4 meals are entered for each day. I decided to include one meal from the second vendor each day. This was done because with 5 options as shown in Part 1, Example 1, meal variety over days didn’t exist. This is also true over weeks with adding in only 1 meal from the second vendor. However, moving to 4 meal from vendor 1, gives me more variety within the day and week. Adding in the second vendor gives variety over weeks. Next, seeing the patterns, represented by the blue and red brackets, shows that similar meal patterns exist every 6 days. Knowing that we’ll be out there for weeks, I wanted to improve upon this. In the Image, day 4, 8, 12, 16, N+4 will be populated by the second vendor’s food entirely. This will give a break to the red/blue cycle and allow me to use even more variety. This next image is what I call, the Nested Diagram, it shows the meals provided by both vendors. As this was a template for my own planning, I switched to using ‘1’s to note a meal without regard to vendor. As a side note the 45th day’s second to last meal breaks the pattern. This was a product of ordering a even number from the second vendor. For meal planning patterns this is where i’m at currently. Look for a future post on further food selection including snacks. I’ll also post up on how we’re going to bag each day’s rations once the food arrives. Image: Nested Diagram Image: In the end i believe the meal plan as shown above provides: a simple meal plan each day (grab a meal and eat from the daily bag) a simple plan over the course of weeks (build it while you’re well rested and on land) a hedge against one vendor having a spoiled meal (packaging issue, placement in boat, etc.) variety of meals for nutrition and flavor Not a requirement but there’s a modicum of cost optimization by using meals of different prices Food Time Comment]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A blog reboot in earnest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A blog reboot in earnest" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basics/2018/04/19/reboot.html"><![CDATA[<p>I hadn’t really put any time into blogging or posting what’s been going on since the beginning of this crazy adventure. But I think i’m turning a corner on ‘why’ I should do this. I need to share back what I’ve learned as this sport/?activity? is in the dark ages compared to just about anything else out there.</p>

<p>I’ve also been crazy busy trying to wrangle together everything i need to do before my flight out to Monterey in May. One way to track that is through posts. :)</p>

<p>Here’s a quick excerpt off the top of my head</p>
<ul>
    <li> Finish my will  </li>
    <li> Buy a different kind of diaper rash cream based on a coworker's suggestion  </li>
    <li> Finish my 75 kilometers of erg'ing meters for the week   </li>
    <li> Send my food supplier my meal list! (Over $2000 in meals not including snacks) </li>
    <li> Send out sponsorship letters for a few remaining items</li>
</ul>

<p>Two notes for today, my 15k erg piece wasn’t fun. The time does go by quickly for the most part but once you notice time, everything slows down. Second note, my new Zhik 160 dinghy boots haven’t needed any breaking in for use with the erg and they feel great even at the end of a piece.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="basics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hadn’t really put any time into blogging or posting what’s been going on since the beginning of this crazy adventure. But I think i’m turning a corner on ‘why’ I should do this. I need to share back what I’ve learned as this sport/?activity? is in the dark ages compared to just about anything else out there. I’ve also been crazy busy trying to wrangle together everything i need to do before my flight out to Monterey in May. One way to track that is through posts. :) Here’s a quick excerpt off the top of my head Finish my will Buy a different kind of diaper rash cream based on a coworker's suggestion Finish my 75 kilometers of erg'ing meters for the week Send my food supplier my meal list! (Over $2000 in meals not including snacks) Send out sponsorship letters for a few remaining items Two notes for today, my 15k erg piece wasn’t fun. The time does go by quickly for the most part but once you notice time, everything slows down. Second note, my new Zhik 160 dinghy boots haven’t needed any breaking in for use with the erg and they feel great even at the end of a piece.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rowing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rowing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rowing" /><published>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rowing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rowing/"><![CDATA[rowing]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rowing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[rowing]]></summary></entry></feed>